<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Workout Planner</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="default_title">My Workout</string>
    <string name="default_set">Sets: 1</string>
    <string name="default_round">Rounds: 0</string>

    <string name="item_name">Workout %1$d</string>
    <string name="item_sets">Total Sets: %1$d</string>
    <string name="item_rounds">Rounds: %1$d</string>
    <string name="name_hint">Name</string>
    <string name="text_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="title_activity_my_workout">MyWorkoutActivity</string>
    <string name="default_name">Name</string>
    <string name="default_descrip">Description for the above set</string>
    <string name="bottom_sheet_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="bottom_sheet_edit">Edit</string>
    <string name="descrip_hint">Description</string>
    <string name="action_about">About</string>

    <!-- \u0020 is a space -->

    <!-- TTS Strings -->
    <string name="tts_starting">Starting in, 5. 4. 3. 2. 1. Begin </string>
    <string name="tts_rest_ending">Rest ending in. </string>
    <string name="tts_round_finished">Round finished, take a break. </string>
    <string name="tts_finished">Finished. </string>
    <string name="tts_take_rest">Take a rest. </string>
    <string name="tts_next_round">Next round. Begin </string>
    <string name="tts_begin">Begin. </string>
    <string name="tts_five">5. </string>
    <string name="tts_four">4. </string>
    <string name="tts_three">3. </string>
    <string name="tts_two">2. </string>
    <string name="tts_one">1. </string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="start_workout_button">Start Workout</string>
    <string name="menu_pause">Pause</string>
    <string name="menu_add_set">Add Set</string>
    <string name="rest_title_text">Rest Time</string>
    <string name="break_title_text">Break Time</string>
    <string name="round_title_text">Rounds</string>
    <string name="default_time">0:30</string>
    <string name="minute_label">M</string>
    <string name="colon">:</string>
    <string name="second_label">S</string>
    <string name="set_number_title">Set Number:</string>
    <string name="default_num">1</string>
    <string name="round_number_title">Round Number:</string>
    <string name="description_label">Description:</string>
    <string name="placeholder_description">Default Description</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="placeholder_title">Title</string>
    <string name="placeholder_number">10</string>
    <string name="no_placeholder">No _____</string>
    <string name="no_rest">No Rest</string>
    <string name="no_break">No Break</string>
    <string name="button_save">Save</string>
    <string name="header_title_default">Default Sets</string>
    <string name="header_title_user_created">User Created</string>
    <string name="header_title_my_sets">My Sets</string>
    <string name="bottom_sheet_dup">Duplicate</string>
    <string name="add_new_set">Add New Set</string>
    <string name="ellipsis">...</string>
    <string name="none_text">None</string>
    <string name="ic_descrip">Icon</string>
    <string name="new_workout">New Workout</string>
    <string name="add_set">Add Set</string>
    <string name="rename_workout">Rename</string>
    <string name="name_error">Name must not be empty!</string>
    <string name="time_error">Time must not be 0.</string>
    <string name="new_set">New Set</string>
    <string name="edit_set">Edit Set</string>
    <string name="total_time_title">Total Time:</string>

    <string-array name="voice_options_titles">
        <item>Male 1</item>
        <item>Male 2</item>
        <item>Female 1</item>
        <item>Female 2</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="voice_options_values">
        <item>M1</item>
        <item>M2</item>
        <item>F1</item>
        <item>F2</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Strings related to Settings -->

    <!-- Example General settings -->
    <string name="pref_header_general">General</string>

    <string name="pref_title_social_recommendations">Enable social recommendations</string>
    <string name="pref_description_social_recommendations">Recommendations for people to contact
        based on your message history
    </string>

    <string name="pref_title_display_name">Display name</string>
    <string name="pref_default_display_name">John Smith</string>

    <string name="pref_title_add_friends_to_messages">Add friends to messages</string>
    <string-array name="pref_example_list_titles">
        <item>Always</item>
        <item>When possible</item>
        <item>Never</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="pref_example_list_values">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>-1</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Example settings for Data & Sync -->
    <string name="pref_header_data_sync">Data &amp; sync</string>

    <string name="pref_title_sync_frequency">Sync frequency</string>
    <string-array name="pref_sync_frequency_titles">
        <item>15 minutes</item>
        <item>30 minutes</item>
        <item>1 hour</item>
        <item>3 hours</item>
        <item>6 hours</item>
        <item>Never</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="pref_sync_frequency_values">
        <item>15</item>
        <item>30</item>
        <item>60</item>
        <item>180</item>
        <item>360</item>
        <item>-1</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="list_preference_entries">
        <item>Entry 1</item>
        <item>Entry 2</item>
        <item>Entry 3</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="list_preference_entry_values">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="multi_select_list_preference_default_value" />

    <string name="pref_title_system_sync_settings">System sync settings</string>

    <!-- Example settings for Notifications -->
    <string name="pref_header_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <string name="pref_title_new_message_notifications">New message notifications</string>

    <string name="pref_title_ringtone">Ringtone</string>
    <string name="pref_ringtone_silent">Silent</string>

    <string name="pref_title_vibrate">Vibrate</string>
    <string name="default_set_title">Set Title</string>
    <string name="set_time_label">Set Time: </string>
    <string name="default_sample_text">This is a block of sample text. Make sure it is changed to something more meaningful.</string>

    <!-- Sets -->
    <string name="descrip_jog">
        Jog at a slow, leisurely pace.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_run">
        Run at a comfortable speed to get the heart pumping.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_walk">
        Walk at a brisk, comfortable pace to cooldown.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_highstep">
        March in place at a reasonable pace, reaching your knees up to a 90 degree angle.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>

    <string name="descrip_pushups">
        Lie on the floor face down and place your hands about shoulder width.\nNext, lower yourself downward until your chest almost touches the floor as you inhale.\nNow breathe out and press your upper body back up to the starting position while squeezing your chest.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_dips">
        For this exercise you will need to place a bench, chair, or stool behind your back. With the bench perpendicular to your body, and while looking away from it, hold on to the bench on its edge with hands separated at shoulder width.\nSlowly lower your body as you inhale by bending at the elbows until you lower yourself.: Keep the elbows as close as possible throughout the movement.\nUsing your triceps to bring your torso up again, lift yourself back to the starting position and repeat.\n\nEquipment: Bench, Chair, Stool
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_curls">
        Stand up straight with a dumbbell in each hand. Keep your elbows close to your torso and rotate your palms up.\nNow, keeping the upper arms stationary, exhale and curl the weights while contracting your biceps. Hold the contracted position for a brief pause as you squeeze your biceps.\nThen, inhale and slowly begin to lower the dumbbells back to the starting position. Repeat.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_shoulderpress">
        While holding a dumbbell in each hand, sit on a bench or stand.\nNow raise the dumbbells to shoulder height one at a time. Make sure to rotate your wrists so that the palms of your hands are facing forward.\nNow, exhale and push the dumbbells upward until they touch at the top.\nThen, after a brief pause at the top contracted position, slowly lower the weights back down to the starting position while inhaling.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_chestpress">
        Lie down on a flat bench with a dumbbell in each hand. The palms of your hands will be facing each other.\nThen, using your thighs to help raise the dumbbells up, lift the dumbbells one at a time so that you can hold them in front of you at shoulder width.\nOnce at shoulder width, rotate your wrists forward so that the palms of your hands are facing away from you. The dumbbells should be just to the sides of your chest.\n\nThen, as you breathe out, use your chest to push the dumbbells up. Lock your arms at the top of the lift and squeeze your chest, hold for a second and then begin coming down slowly.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells, Bunch
    </string>

    <string name="descrip_squats">
        Stand with your feet shoulder width apart. Place your hands behind your head.\nBegin the movement by flexing your knees and hips, sitting back with your hips.\nContinue down to full depth if you are able, and quickly reverse the motion until you return to the starting position. As you squat, keep your head and chest up and push your knees out.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_wallsquats">
        Begin with your back against the wall and your feet out in front of you. Have your feet shoulder width apart.\nDescend slowly by sliding down the wall. Keep your head up and maintain a flat back against the wall.\nContinue down until the upper legs are at or just below parallel to the floor. Maintain this position for an amount of time. Focus on breathing continuously throughout.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>

    <string name="descrip_situps">
        Lie flat on your back with your feet flat on the ground.\nNow place your hands lightly on either side of your head keeping your elbows in. Don\'t lock your fingers behind your head.\nPush down as hard as you can with your lower back as you contract your abdominals and exhale. Your shoulders should come up off the floor only about four inches, and your lower back should remain on the floor.\nAfter the one second contraction, begin to come down slowly again to the starting position as you inhale.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_plank">
        Get into a prone position on the floor, supporting your weight on your toes and your forearms. Your arms are bent and directly below the shoulder.\nKeep your body straight at all times, and hold this position as long as possible.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_upperrow">
        With a dumbbell in each hand (palms facing your torso), bend your knees slightly and bring your torso forward by bending at the waist; as you bend make sure to keep your back straight until it is almost parallel to the floor.\nMake sure that you keep the head up. The weights should hang directly in front of you as your arms hang perpendicular to the floor and your torso.\nWhile keeping the torso stationary, lift the dumbbells to your side, keeping the elbows close to the body. On the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a second.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_stepup">
        Stand up straight while holding a dumbbell in each hand (palms facing the side of your legs).\nPlace your right foot on the elevated platform. Step on the platform by extending your right hip and knee. Use the heel mainly to lift the rest of your body up and place your left foot on the platform as well.\nStep down with the left leg by flexing your right hip and knee as you inhale.\nAlternate between your right and left leg.\n\nEquipment: Steps or Bench, Dumbbells (Optional)
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_reverselunge">
        Stand with your torso upright holding two dumbbells (Optional) in your hands by your sides.\nStep backwards with your right leg around 2 feet while keeping the torso upright and maintaining balance. Inhale as you go down.\nUsing mainly the heel of your foot, push up and go back to the starting position as you exhale.\nRepeat alternating legs.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells (Optional)
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_sidelunge">
        Stand with your torso upright, kneeds slightly bent.\nStaying low, take a slow, lateral step to the right. Keep your toes pointed forward and stay low.\nExtend the left knee, driving your weight to the right, flexing the knee and hip into a side lunge. Keep your head and chest up.\nRepeat alternating legs.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_airbike">
        Lie flat on the floor with your lower back pressed to the ground. Put your hands beside your head. Lift your shoulders into the crunch position.\nBring knees up to where they are perpendicular to the floor, with your lower legs parallel to the floor.\nNow simultaneously, slowly go through a cycle pedal motion kicking forward with the right leg and bringing in the knee of the left leg. Bring your right elbow close to your left knee by crunching to the side, as you breathe out.\nCrunch to the opposite side as you cycle your legs and bring closer your left elbow to your right knee. Continue alternating sides.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_tplank">
        Get into a prone position on the floor, supporting your weight on your toes and your forearms. Your arms are bent and directly below the shoulder.\nKeep your body straight at all times. Pivot to one side, raising an arm vertically above you as you twist.\nPause and return to the starting position, and then repeat on the other side.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_jumpingjack">
        Start by standing with your feet together. In one motion, jump your feet out to the side and raise your arms above your head.\nJump back to the starting position and repeat.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_buttkickers">
        Stand with your legs shoulder-width apart. Your arms should be bent at your sides.\nJog in place while bringing your heels up to your glutes.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_mountain_climbers">
        Begin in a pushup position, with your weight supported by your hands and toes. Flexing the knee and hip, bring one leg in until the knee is approximately under the hip.\nExplosively reverse the positions of your legs, extending the bent leg until the leg is straight and supported by the toe, and bringing the other foot up with the hip and knee flexed.\nRepeat alternating legs.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_leg_raises">
        Lie with your back flat on the floor or a bench and your legs extended in front of you.\nPlace your hands either under your glutes with your palms down or by the sides.\nAs you keep your legs extended, straight as possible with your knees slightly bent but locked raise your legs until they make a 90-degree angle with the floor. Exhale and hold the contraction at the top for a second.\nNow, as you inhale, slowly lower your legs back down to the starting position.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: Bench (Optional)
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_pile_squat">
        Start off standing with your feet 2-4 inches wider than your shoulders, with your toes pointed out.\nGrab onto a dumbbell with both hands in the center of your body making sure that you keep your knees slightly bent and your back straight.\nSquat down as if you were going to sit in a chair, bringing your thighs parallel to the floor.\nReturn to a standing position and repeat.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbell
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_squat_jumps">
        Start with your arms by your side, feet shoulder width apart, head up, and back straight.\nKeeping your back straight and chest up, squat down as you inhale until your upper thighs are parallel, or lower, to the floor.\nNow pressing mainly with the balls of your feet, jump straight up in the air as high as possible, using the thighs like springs.\nRepeat as your touch the floor.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_reverse_crunch">
        Lie down on the floor with your legs fully extended and arms to your side with the palms on the floor.\nMove your legs up so that your thighs are perpendicular to the floor and feet are together and parallel to the floor.\nWhile inhaling, move your legs towards the torso as you roll your pelvis backwards and you raise your hips off the floor. At the end of this movement your knees will be touching your chest.\nHold the contraction for a second and move your legs back.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_shoulder_press_squats">
        Begin in a standing position with a dumbbell in each hand. Your palms should be facing each other. Look directly forward, keep your chest up, and place your feet about shoulder-width apart.\nInitiate the movement with a squat, flexing the knees and hips to lower your body. Descend as far as flexibility allows.\nPause for a brief moment at the bottom of the squat before returning to a standing position by extending the hips and knees.\nAfter fully rising to a standing position, press the weights overhead by extending the elbows and flexing at the shoulder.\nReturn the weights to the shoulder before repeating.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_arm_raise_plank">
        Get into a prone position on the floor, supporting your weight on your toes and your forearms. Your arms are bent and directly below the shoulder.\nKeeping your body straight, hold this position for as long as possible while raising one arm straight out ahead of you.\nAlternate arms while keeping your body straight.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_superman">
        To begin, lie straight and face down on the floor. Your arms should be fully extended in front of you.\nSimultaneously raise your arms, legs, and chest off of the floor and hold this contraction for 2 seconds.\nSlowly begin to lower your arms, legs and chest back down to the starting position while inhaling.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_plank_jumps">
        Start in a basic plank position, supporting yourself on your hands and toes, hands shoulder width apart.\nSet your shoulder blades so that your upper body doesn\'t move. Jump your feet in towards your hands then jump your feet back out into a plank and repeat, alternating sides.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_burpees">
        Begin standing with your legs shoulder-width apart.\nPlace your hands on the floor and kick your legs back so you end up with your stomach and thighs on the floor. Your elbows should be bent.\nFrom this position, press up like you\'re doing a push-up and push your hips up.\nJump your feet under your hips and stand.\nFinish the movement by jumping in the air and bringing your hands over your head.\nRepeat.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_plankjacks">
        Begin in plank position, with your hands shoulder width apart, your body in one straight line, and your feet together.\nLike the motion of a jumping jack, jump your legs wide and then back together.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_legpulls">
        Lie on the floor with your legs extended and your hands either palms facing down next to you or under your glutes.\nBend your knees and pull your upper thighs into your midsection as you breathe out. Continue the motion until your knees are around chest level. Contract your abs and hold for a second at the top.\nReturn to starting position and repeat.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_toe_touch">
        Standing up straight, bend at the waist, keeping your legs straight, until you can relax and let your upper body hang down in front of you.\nLet your arms and hands hang down naturally. Hold for 10 to 20 seconds. Repeat\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_arm_cross">
        Reach your left arm across your body and hold it straight\nWith your right hand, grasp your left elbow and pull it across your body towards your chest.\nHold for fifteen seconds and switch arms.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_butterfly">
        Sit on the floor with back straight.\nBring in your legs until your feet are touching, and bring in as close as you feel comfortable.\nUsing you hands to hold your feet, bend forward slightly and flex you knees down as much as possible.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>

    <string name="descrip_lunges">
        Stand with your torso upright holding two dumbbells (Optional) in your hands by your sides.\nStep forward with your right leg around 2 feet while keeping the torso upright and maintaining balance. Inhale as you go down.\nUsing mainly the heel of your foot, push up and go back to the starting position as you exhale.\nRepeat alternating legs.\n\nEquipment: Dumbbells (Optional)
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_arm_spins">
        Stand up and extend your arms straight out by the sides. The arms should be parallel to the floor.\nSlowly start to make circles of about 1 foot in diameter with each outstretched arm.\nContinue the circular motion of the outstretched arms for about ten seconds. Then reverse the movement, going the opposite direction.\n\nEquipment: None
    </string>

    <string name="descrip_study">
        Concentrate on studying with no distractions.
    </string>
    <string name="descrip_studybreak">
        Take a small break from studying.\nDo not engage in any activities that require too much focus.
    </string>
    <string name="sets_title">Sets:</string>
    <string name="content_equipment_required">Equipment Required</string>
    <string name="content_default_image">image</string>
    <string name="credits">
        App icon designed by Darius Dan from Flaticon.\nThis app is not affiliated with Bodybuilding.com. The content on their website is for informational and educational purposes.\nApp designed and programmed by Tyler Welsh.
    </string>
    <string name="rest_name">Rest</string>
    <string name="rest_descrip_display">Take a short rest. Do not sit or lie down.</string>
    <string name="break_name">Break Time</string>
    <string name="break_descrip_display">Take a longer rest. Move around and drink some water</string>
    <string name="finished_name">Finished</string>
    <string name="footer_add_workout">Add Workout</string>
    <string name="equipment_required">Equipment Required</string>


    <string name="ad_key">ca-app-pub-1633767409472368~4737915463</string>
    <string name="banner_key">ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/6300978111</string>
    <string name="add_a_set">Please add at least one set!</string>
    <!-- Test Key : ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/6300978111
         Real Key : ca-app-pub-1633767409472368/2167592441 -->



</resources>
